－那就是你最担心的事  －对 任何一种病毒
And that's your biggest worry? Yes, any kind of virus,
但最可能是类似流感的东西
but most probably something similar to influenza.
因为空中旅行
Because of air travel.
透过空气传播 像是咳嗽
Through the air.
－还有… －不好意思 我是指人们搭乘飞机
- Coughing-- - I'm sorry. I meant people. On planes.
你的书里有提到
That was something you described in your book.
没错 马达加斯加的新病毒 可能会在几周内传到芝加哥
Yes, a new virus in Madagascar, say, could be in Chicago within a matter of weeks.
最后造成全球性的大流行病
And we end up with a global pandemic. Pan meaning "all."
意思就是全世界的人都同时染疫
The whole world becomes sick all at once.
纽曼博士 你也是流行病学家
And, Dr. Neuman, you're also an epidemiologist.
我想病毒造成大规模疫情的可能性 也让你辗转难眠吧
I presume the prospect of a viral pandemic keeps you up at night as well.
－并没有 －是吗
- No. - No?
－并没有 －好吧 今天节目就到这里
- No. - All right, well, that's our show.
不 人类一直以来都在与病毒交战
No, mankind has been at war with the virus from the start.
有时甚至和真正的战争一样 死亡人数高达数百万
Sometimes, millions of people die, as in an actual war.
但到头来 我们永远是赢家
But in the end, we always win.
我们先厘清一点 你确实认为微生物是种威胁
But you-- just to be clear, you do think microorganisms pose a threat.
是很严峻的威胁
In the most dire terms.
－细菌  －不是
- Bacteria. - No.
－你喜欢否定别人 －没错
- You like saying no. - Yes.
不是细菌 不是病毒 所以是…
Not bacteria. Not viruses. - So?
真菌
- Fungus.
没错 这是常见的反应
Yes, that's the usual response.
真菌似乎挺无害的
Fungi seem harmless enough.
许多物种却知道事实并非如此
Many species know otherwise.
因为有些真菌寻求的不是杀戮
Because there are some fungi who seek not to kill,
而是控制
but to control.
我问你 迷幻药是从哪里来的
Let me ask you, where do we get LSD from?
你又是从哪里拿到的
Where do you get it from?
它来自麦角 一种真菌
It comes from ergot, a fungus.
还有神奇蘑菇 也是真菌
Psilocybin? Also a fungus.
病毒会让我们生病 但真菌能改变我们的心智
Viruses can make us ill, but fungi can alter our very minds.
有一种真菌会感染昆虫
There's a fungus that infects insects.
比方说入侵蚂蚁的身体
Gets inside an ant, for example,
透过循环系统进入蚂蚁的大脑
travels through its circulatory system to the ant's brain,
让大脑充满迷幻药 从而使蚂蚁的心智屈服于其意志
and then floods it with hallucinogens, thus bending the ant's mind to its will.
真菌开始指挥蚂蚁的行为
The fungus starts to direct the ant's behavior,
告诉它该去哪里 该做什么
telling it where to go, what to do,
就像操偶师操纵牵线木偶那样
like a puppeteer with a marionette.
而且情况还会更糟
And it gets worse.
真菌需要食物才能存活
The fungus needs food to live,
所以它会开始从体内吞噬宿主
so it begins to devour its host from within,
用自己的组织取代蚂蚁的肉体
replacing the ant's flesh with its own,
但它不会让受害者死去 不
but it doesn't let its victim die.
它会防止受害者腐烂 让傀儡继续活下去
No, it keeps its puppet alive by preventing decomposition.
怎么办到
How?
－盘尼西林从哪里来  －真菌
Where do we get penicillin from? Fungus.
－萧恩海斯博士 你不同意  －这种真菌感染确实存在
Dr. Schoenheiss, you're in distress. Fungal infection of this kind is real,
但不会发生在人类身上
but not in humans.
没错 如果宿主的体内温度 超过华氏９４度
True, fungi cannot survive if its host's internal temperature is over 94 degrees.
真菌的确无法存活
And currently,
而且目前真菌没有理由
there are no reasons for fungi to evolve
进化到能够承受更高的温度
to be able to withstand higher temperatures.
但要是情况改变了呢 譬如说…
But what if that were to change? What if,
地球的温度稍微上升了一点
for instance, the world were to get slightly warmer?
那就有进化的理由了
Well, now there is reason to evolve.
只要出现一次基因突变
One gene mutates
一种子囊菌 像是念珠菌 麦角
and an ascomycete, candida, ergot,
虫草菌 曲菌等
cordyceps, aspergillus,
任何一种都有可能钻进我们的大脑
any one of them could become capable of burrowing into our brains
进而控制人类 而且不是数百万人 是数十亿人
and taking control not of millions of us, but billions of us.
数十亿个心智遭到毒害的傀儡
Billions of puppets with poisoned minds
永远锁定一个统一的目标
permanently fixed on one unifying goal:
用尽一切必要手段感染每一个…
to spread the infection to every last human alive
还活着的人
by any means necessary.
这种病没有治疗方法 没有预防措施 没有解药
And there are no treatments for this. No preventatives, no cures.
解药不存在 甚至不可能制造出来
They don't exist. It's not even possible to make them.
所以如果发生那种事…
So, if that happens?
我们就输了
We lose.
我们稍后回来
We'll be back.
最后生还者
第一季第一集
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
（２００３年）
（和平）
闹钟响了
Alarm.
Alarm!
松饼粉呢
- Where's the pancake mix?
用完了吗
- Oh, was I--
对 用完了 抱歉
Yeah, I was. Sorry.
我本来要帮你做生日松饼的 真是的
I was gonna make you birthday pancakes. I swear.
我其实不喜欢松饼
You know I don't really like pancakes.
我知道你不喜欢 是我自己想吃
I know you don't like them. It was for my benefit.
要补充维他命Ｃ
Vitamin C.
功课做完了吗
You get your homework done?
在学分数吗
Fractions?
你现在是几岁
How old are you again?
３６岁
Thirty-six.
－很快就得穿尿布了 －谁说我还没穿
Gonna have to wear diapers soon. Who says I don't already?
－有蛋壳 －补充钙质
Shell. Calcium.
很好
Lovely.
够汤米叔叔吃吗
Is there enough for Uncle Tommy?
本来够的
Well, there would've been.
你好
还活着啊 你这老混蛋
You're still alive, you old fucker.
－他爱你 －他靠我过活 这不一样
He loves you. He's dependent on me. Not the same.
－我觉得一样 －绝对一样
- I think it's the same. - It's definitely the same.
我以为我们要吃松饼
I thought we was havin' pancakes.
我会在路上帮你买吃的
We'll pick you somethin' up on the road.
－水泥工也会去吗  －他们说也许会
- Concrete guys gonna be there? - Yeah, they said maybe.
也许 没灌浆就不能做构架 没构架就拿不到钱
Maybe? We can't frame until we pour. We're not gettin' paid until we frame.
可以找别人来 这样会更快完工
Well, we could bring someone else on, get the job done faster.
不行 我不要跟别人合作这个案子
- No, no. I'm not splittin' this job.
连跟你合作我都不太甘愿了
I barely wanna split it with you.
我们可以加班
We could work a double.
不是吧
- Literally?
－今天加班  －我知道 我九点前会结束
Today? - I know. I'd be done by nine.
九点 对吧
By nine, right?
对
Yeah.
我会带蛋糕回来
I'll bring back a cake.
我保证
I promise.
雅加达持续发生动乱 政府仍建议美国公民…
...continued disturbances in Jakarta, but are advising U.S. citizens...
雅加达 那是哪里 中东吗
Jakarta. Where is that, Middle East?
没印象 绝对是个国家
Doesn't ring a bell. It's definitely a country.
或者是亚洲的一部分
- Or maybe part of Asia?
雅加达不是一个国家
- Jakarta isn't a country.
作为亚洲的一部分 不代表一定不是国家
Being a part of Asia isn't mutually exclusive with being a country,
事实上 雅加达是印尼的首都
and in fact, it's the capital of Indonesia.
天啊 看来未来还有希望
Shit. Hope for us yet.
雅加达的人口…
好
All right.
快点吃完 我们送你上学
Finish up quick, we'll drop you off.
－我还在吃蛋壳 －你还有七分钟
- I'm still eating my eggshells. - You got seven minutes.
你的Ｔ恤里外穿反了
Your t-shirt's inside out.
该死
Shit.
他要疯了
He's losin' it.
建议民众尽快离开该国
莎拉
Sarah!
你好 邻居
Hey, neighbor!
你们好
Oh, Hi.
康妮问起你
Connie was askin' after you,
因为你有一阵子没来了
since you haven't been over in a while.
配合一下吧
Make 'em happy.
我放学后可以过去 但只能一下下
I could come by after school, but just for, like, a little bit?
她都可以
- She'll take whatcha got.
你们可以一起烘焙什么的
Y'all can bake, whatever.
说到这个
Speakin' of,
我们还有很多饼干
we got a lotta extra here.
你们想来一点吗
Y'all want some biscuits?
爸 你最爱饼干了
Dad, you love biscuits.
没错
I do.
但我在采取艾金斯饮食法
But I'm on Atkins.
－什么东西  －就是…
- On what now? - It's,
你知道吗 我们得走了 但莎拉晚点会过去
you know what? We gotta run, but Sarah'll be by later.
你要她待多久都行
She'll stay as long as you want.
－她会跟你介绍艾金斯饮食法的一切 －太好了
Tell ya all about Atkins. Great!
我会转告康妮的
I'll let Connie know.
算你狠
Solid.
听到这样的对话还真是刺激啊
Can't tell you how exciting it was listenin' to that fuckin' conversation.
把烟熄掉
Put that out.
祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday to you.
（沙漠风暴行动退伍军人）
OPERATION DESERT STORM COMBAT VETERAN
（德州 奥斯丁 ９月２６日）
AUSTIN, TX SEPTEMBER 26th
我要你们把这个图表 一字不漏地抄下来
Want you to write this diagram out exactly as I have it.
一定要有主词 述词
Always subject and predicate.
动词和名词
Verb and noun.
好 句子是“你要去哪里 ”
Okay, the sentence is, "Where are you going?"
主词是“你”
Subject is you.
“你要去”
You are going.
述词 “哪里” 副词
Predicate. Where, adverb.
懂吗 好 我看到有些人点头 有些人摇头
You see it? Okay. Have some nods, shaking of heads.
我发誓你们以后一定会用到
I swear you will use this later in life.
相信我 这就是为什么 我们现在要学这些
Believe me, that's why you're here.
“你”是主词 主词一定要接动词
Okay? So...
就在上面 我写在那边就是为了让你们记住
没错 你们一定要知道
Yes, you need to know this!
下星期的考试会考
Yes, it's on your test next week!
明天下课前要交作业
Homework is due end of class tomorrow!
２０元
Twenty.
就这样
That's it?
好 那３０元
Okay, 30.
２０元可以
Twenty's good.
是弹簧出了问题 我现在就修
It's a spring. I'll do it right now.
整天都这样 真是的
All day. I swear.
我们要打烊了
We're closing.
（外语）
我们要关门了
We're done for today.
现在才３点１５分 我们７点关门
It's 3:15, we close at 7.
（外语）
－我很抱歉 他没办法做完 －我已经修好了
- I'm very sorry. He cannot finish. - I'm already finished.
（外语）
你该回家了
You should go home.
（营业中）
－你终于来了 亲爱的 －抱歉
- There you are, sweetie. - Sorry.
我都开始担心了
I was gettin' worried.
我去拿要给我爸的东西
I was getting something for my dad.
你好 梅西
Hi, Mercy.
一切都还好吧
Hey, is everything okay?
有什么新闻吗
Like, on the news?
你是指什么 甜心
Like what, hon?
也没什么 只是今天路上有很多警察
Well, no, there was just a lot of police and stuff on the road today.
每天都这样 不是吗
Well, that's true every day, innit?
人们应该要向耶稣忏悔
People out there need to get right with Jesus.
三根钉子加一个十字架等于宽恕
Three nails, plus one cross, equals four-given.
我们可以来做饼干
I was thinkin' we'd make some cookies.
巧克力碎片
Chocolate chip?
葡萄干
Raisin.
吃啊 妈
C'mon, Mama.
这是绿色的
It's green.
你最爱了
You love that.
好了
Here we go!
我不知道为什么我要跟她说话
I don't know why I talk to her.
她已经完全听不见了
She's completely deaf.
你要来帮我吗
You wanna give me a hand?
马上来
Be right there!
艾德勒太太
Hey, Mrs. Adler?
这个可以借我吗
Could I borrow this?
当然可以 这是丹尼的
Yeah, sure. It's one of Danny's.
我爸很快就会回来 我该走了
You know what? My dad's gonna be back real soon. - I should go.
－你确定  －对
- You sure? - Yeah.
你要带些饼干走
- Well, you're takin' some cookies.
奥斯丁警局
今天对城内爆发的一连串暴力事件 不予置评
No comment today from the Austin Police Department regarding a rash of violent incidents across the city,
有人认为罪魁祸首 可能是新的街头毒品
some suggesting a new street drug may be to blame.
稍后回来
More on that when we return,
记者曼纽拉桑切斯 将在总部进行现场报导
with Manuela Sanchez reporting live...
你终于记得锁门了
You locked the door for once.
做得好
Good job.
是啊
Yeah.
－都十点了 －我知道
- It's 10. - I know.
他们给的顶梁尺寸不对
They gave us the wrong size for the headers.
那对你来说毫无意义 对不起
That doesn't mean anything to ya. I'm sorry.
蛋糕在哪
Where's the cake?
该死
- Shit.
－拜托 －我明天再买
- C'mon, man. I'll get us one tomorrow.
你发誓
Swear,
不然你就没礼物了
or you don't get your present.
你为我准备了礼物
- You got me a present?
你先发誓
- Swear.
以我的性命发誓
On my life.
瞧瞧
Wow.
我帮你修好了
Fixed it for you.
－有吗  －什么
- Did you? - What?
我什么都没听到
I don't hear anything.
这招很逊
That was lame.
－你很逊 －对 我知道
- You're lame. - Yeah, I know.
你哪来的钱
Where'd you get the money for this?
－我是药头 专卖强力毒品 －比我的工作强多了
Drugs. I sell hardcore drugs. It's better than what I do.
才花了２０元 我从你那里偷来的
It was only $20, which I stole from you.
我本来可以偷６０元
I could've stolen 60,
但我把零钱放回去了 因为我盗亦有道
but I put the change back because I'm an honest thief.
而且 心意最重要
Besides, it's the thought that counts.
你永远不会为自己这么做 所以…
And you were never gonna do it for yourself, so.
谢谢你
Thank you.
还有一个
There's one more.
跟艾德勒家借的
- Borrowed it from the Adlers.
－这是有包含删减片段的 －对
- This is the one with the deleted scenes. Yeah,
想想是有多烂才会被删
imagine how bad those have to be.
开始播吧 趁现在还是你的生日
C'mon, pop it in. While it's still your birthday.
别睡着了
- Don't fall asleep.
当然不会 那么精彩
-'Course, I won't. It's too riveting.
你好
Hello?
乔尔 是我
Joel, it's me.
我没事
I'm okay.
－是吗  －但我在牢里
- Yeah? -But I'm in jail.
－该死 －这次不是我的错
- Goddammit. -Wasn't my fault this time.
我在酒吧 有个家伙突然抓狂 开始殴打女服务生
I was at the bar, some guy goes crazy, starts swingin' at a waitress,
我插手 把他打昏 警察就出现了
I stepped in, knocked him out, cops show up--
听着 这不重要 你得保我出去
Look, it doesn't fuckin' matter. -You gotta bail me out.
－现在  －今天是星期五
- Now? It's Friday,
今晚你不保我出去 我整个周末都得待在这里
you don't get me out tonight, I'm in here all weekend.
这里简直是疯人院 乔尔 我得出去
It's a fuckin' madhouse, Joel. -I gotta get out.
哪间看守所 崔维斯郡
- Well, which jail? Travis County?
对 在第十街
Yeah, on 10th.
该死 汤米
- Goddammit, Tommy.
抱歉
-I'm sorry.
拜托
Please.
好吧
Okay.
该死的白痴
Fuckin' idiot.
11:03 PM
爸
Dad?
Dad?!
请待在室内
...indoors.
执法人员和紧急服务人员已经出动
Law enforcement and emergency services are in the area
请等候进一步指示
and will be in contact with further instructions.
请待在室内
Stay indoors,
执法人员…
law enforcement...
冷静点 梅西
Easy. Easy, Mercy.
你怎么会在这里
What're you doing out here, boy?
来 我带你回家
C'mon, let's get you home.
走吧 梅西 拜托
C'mon, Mercy. Please.
梅西
Mercy!
艾德勒太太
Mrs. Adler?
救我
Help me.
上车 快
Get in the truck! Right now!
快
Move!
怎么办 乔尔
What are we doin', Joel?
－你杀了她 －宝贝 对不起
- You killed her. - Baby, I'm sorry.
－乔尔 我们得走了 －莎拉 听我说
- Joel, we gotta go. - Sarah, listen to me.
不只是艾德勒家这样
It's not just the Adlers.
但我们要勇敢 我们会逃出去的
But we're gonna be brave, and we're gonna get outta this.
我们走吧 快
Hey. Let's go. Come on.
上车
Get in.
乔尔
Joel?
丹妮丝 回屋里去
Denise, you get back inside the house!
把门锁上 快点
- You lock your doors! Now!
快点上车
- C'mon, c'mon, get in!
－系上安全带 －抓紧了
- Get your seat belt on. - Hold on.
天啊 乔尔
Jesus Christ, Joel!
－你走７１… －７１号公路 我知道
- You take 70-- - 71, I know.
（奥斯丁 圣马克斯）
AUSTIN SAN MARCOS
－爸  －我们不知道
- Daddy-- - We don't know.
他们说是病毒或某种寄生虫
They're saying it's a virus. Some kind of parasite.
是恐怖分子干的吗
Is it from terrorists?
我们不知道
We don't know.
－我们也生病了吗  －不 当然没有
- Are we sick? - No. Of course not.
－为什么都没有消息  －没有手机讯号 没有广播
Why did things blow up? No cellphone, no radio.
一分钟前新闻还报个不停
Minute ago, newsman wouldn't shut up.
－你怎么知道  －什么
- How do you know? - What?
你怎么知道我们没生病
How do you know we're not sick?
他们说大部分是市区的人受感染
They're saying it's mostly people in the city.
所以他们才封锁高速公路
That's why they got the highway blocked off.
天啊
God.
那是吉米家
It's Jimmy's place.
艾德勒家会带婆婆进城
The Adlers would take Nana into the city.
去医院看病
To the hospital for stuff.
没错 他们会那么做
That's right. They would.
那可能就是原因
That's probably why.
但要很常去才会得
But, you'd have to go a lot,
对吧
right?
你没事的 相信我
We're fine. Trust me.
好
All right.
等等 慢一点 停车
Here! Right here!
－你在干什么  －他们有小孩 乔尔
- Hey! - What are you doin'? - Got a kid, Joel.
－我们也有 继续开 －等等 请停车
- So do we. Keep driving.
－我们可以让他们坐后面 －不…拜托
We could put them in the back.
回来 回来啊
拜托
会有其他人经过的
Somebody else'll come along.
该死 每个人都打着一样的主意
Fuck! Everybody had the same fuckin' idea.
－我过不去 －好 我们好好想想
I can't get through this. All right. Let's think it through, we'll think it through.
－该死 －走空地
- Fuck! - All right, take the field.
我们切过去从西边上公路
We cut across and we pick up on the west side.
好…西边…好 坐稳了
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. West, west, all right. All right, hang on.
可恶 是该死的军队
Shit! Fuckin' army.
那不是好事吗
- Isn't that good?
对他们来说是好事 但那是我们要走的公路
- It's good for them, but that's the highway we're tryin' to get to.
－继续开 往北走 －会有很多人
All right, keep movin'. Head north. - Could be a lotta people.
我们不能往南 不能往东 不能往西
- Well, we can't go south, we can't go east, we can't go west.
不然我们还能去哪
Hell else we supposed to go?
汤米 快点
Tommy, come on!
对
Yeah.
－这地方我认得 应该行得通 －但然后呢
Yeah, I know that place. - This can work. - Yeah, but then what?
我不知道 去墨西哥 越远越好 还剩多少汽油
I don't know. Mexico. Just far, far as we can. - How much gas?
－四分之三油箱 －好
- Three-quarter tank.
我们走市区 穿过河边的高尔夫球场
Go through town, golf course by the river, straight across,
在路障的另一边接上高速公路 然后我们就脱身了
we pick up the highway on the other side of the blockade, then we're out.
也许已经蔓延到各地了
Maybe it's everywhere.
也许我们无处可去
Maybe there's nowhere to go.
搞什么
What the fuck?!
该死 得要绕过去
Son of a bitch. Gotta go around.
抓稳
Grab somethin'!
－该死 看看他们 －好 继续走…
All right, keep goin', keep goin'.
－该死 －汤米
Shit. Tommy!
天啊
快点
汤米 你不能停在这里
Tommy, you can't stop here.
－我没办法撞过去 －你是认真的吗 继续开
- I can't drive through 'em all. - Are you serious?
好啦
Just keep goin'!
－倒车… －我在试了
Go, go, go. Back, back, back, back, back, back, back! - I'm trying!
该死
－汤米 快点 我们要赶快离开 －我在试了 没地方可去
Tommy, go faster! We gotta go! I'm tryin'! There's nowhere to fuckin' go!
－找条巷子 －什么巷子 到处都是人
- Find an alley! - What alley? - There's people everywhere!
从他们身上辗过去 我们得立刻离开这条街
- Roll the fuck over them! We gotta get off this street now!
我正在努力那么做 乔尔
That's what I'm tryin' to do, Joel.
我们会没事的 继续前进就好
We're gonna be okay. Just keep drivin'.
爸
Dad?
该死
Holy shit!
快走…
Move. Move!
莎拉…待在那里别动
Sarah, Sarah. Stay right there. Don't move.
－汤米 你没事吧  －我没事
Tommy, you okay? Yeah, I'm okay.
莎拉 别看
Sarah, don't look.
看着我就好 好吗
You look at me, okay?
抱歉 宝贝 我知道很痛 我知道
I'm sorry, baby, I know, I know. Come here. Put your arms around me.
抱着我 来…
Come here, come here.
我抱住你了…
I got you. I got you.
我抱住你了
Got you.
你还好吗 没事吧
Are you okay? Are you okay?
－我的脚踝 －好
- My ankle. - All right, okay.
我们得离开这条街
We gotta get off the street!
该死
Shit!
汤米
Tommy?!
Tommy?
汤米
Tommy!
去河边 我会自己想办法
Head to the river! I'll find a way.
带她离开 乔尔 快走
Get her outta here, Joel! Go!
－我们不能丢下他 －他不会有事的 你能跑吗
- We can't leave him. - He'll be fine. - Can you run?
不行
- No.
－眼睛看着我 好吗  －好
- You keep your eyes on me. - Okay.
－好 －别看其他地方
- Okay? - Okay. And don't look anywhere else.
好
Alright.
爸
没事了 亲爱的 你安全了
It's okay, baby. You're safe.
不准动
Don't move!
－我女儿受伤了 她的脚踝… －站住
- My daughter's hurt. Her ankle. - Stop right there!
好
Okay.
放轻松 我们没病
Easy now. We're not sick!
河边有两个平民 一人受伤
I got two civilians by the river, one of 'em injured.
脚踝
Ankle.
汤米叔叔怎么办
What about Uncle Tommy?
我们先让你到安全的地方
We're gonna get you somewhere safe first.
－然后再回去找他 好吗  －好
Then we'll go back for him, okay? - Okay.
－好 －抱歉 再说一次
- Okay.  I'm sorry, repeat?
站住 谁叫你们动了
Hey! No one told you to move.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
我们没有病
We're not sick.
长官
Sir,
我们没有病
we are not sick!
对不起
I'm sorry.
拜托不要
Please, don't.
天啊
Oh God.
不
No. Oh no.
不…
No, no. No.
好 你没事的
Okay, You're okay.
你没事 手拿开 宝贝
You're okay. Move your hand, baby.
手拿开
Move your hand.
不 我知道 宝贝 我知道…
I know, baby, I know, I know, I know, I know.
我知道很痛
I know it hurts.
好了 来…
Alright. Don't look down, look up, look up.
加油 宝贝 你没事的
Come on, baby. You're okay, you're okay.
我知道…宝贝 我知道…
I know, I know, I know, I know, baby, I know, I know.
我知道很痛
I know this hurts.
你会没事的 好吗
You're gonna be okay.
宝贝…听我说
All right, baby, baby, baby, listen to me.
我得扶你起来 好吗
I gotta get you up, okay?
我得扶你起来 可以吗
I gotta get you up. All right?
来…
You come on. You come on.
我知道 宝贝
I know, baby.
我知道…
No, no. I know, I know, I know, I know, I know, I know.
汤米 帮帮我
Tommy, help me!
乔尔
Joel.
来 宝贝女儿 我得扶你起来 快
C'mon, baby girl. C'mon, baby girl, I gotta get you up. Come on.
来 我们得走了 快点 宝贝女儿
Come on, we'll get up. Come on, baby girl.
拜托
Come on,
拜托…求求你
come-- Please.
（二十年后）
TWENTY YEARS LATER
（波士顿）
BOSTON
（２０２３年）
（欢迎）
WELCOME
（请通报虫草菌感染迹象）
（咳嗽 口齿不清 肌肉痉挛 性格骤变）
（注意安全 以身作则）
（感染进程）
我们不希望你从椅子上摔下来
We don't want you falling out of the chair.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
你一个人吗
Are you alone?
还有…
And,
这是怎么了
how did you get this?
这里会有点痒
There's gonna be a little tickle right here.
如果我告诉你 在我们给你一些药之后
What if I told you that after we gave you some medicine,
我们会给你你最爱吃的食物怎么样
we're gonna find you your favorite food to eat.
你想吗
Would you like that?
然后我们会给你些新衣服和玩具
And then we'll get you some new clothes... and toys.
你想玩多少就玩多少
As many as you wanna play with.
只是个小针头
It's just a little needle.
没事的
It's okay.
你很安全
You're safe.
我做不到
I can't.
十张
Ten.
有别的工作吗
- You got anything else?
今天没有 明天有清扫街道
- Nothin' today. Tomorrow, we got street sweeping,
或维护下水道
or sewer maintenance.
哪个薪水比较高
Which pays more?
会碰到大便的那个
That'd be the one with the shit.
晚班 下午四点开始
Late crew. 4 P.M. start.
（宵禁时间 晚上六点至早上六点）
CURFEW HOURS 6PM - 6AM
（未经允许外出 将被立即逮捕）
ANYONE ON THE STREET WITHOUT FEDERAL APPROVAL IS SUBJECT TO IMMEDIATE ARREST
（请通报虫草菌感染迹象）
（鞋带 一张配给卡 靴带 两张配给卡）
SHOE LACES 1 RATION CARD EACH BOOT LACES 2 RATION CARDS EACH SEARCH FOR THE LIGHT
杰森蔡 违反环境管理条约 第３４２点３条
Jason Choi, violation of EMC 342.3,
未经授权离开隔离区
unauthorized exit from a Quarantine Zone.
玛丽亚艾利西安诺 违反环境管理条约第３４２点７条
Maria Elisiano, violation of EMC 342.7,
未经授权进入隔离区
unauthorized entry into a Quarantine Zone.
你们每一位皆已在军事法庭受审
Each of you have been tried in a military court of justice,
并被军法审判团判处有罪
and each of you having been found guilty by the court martial panel,
处以死刑
and with a sentence of death by execution,
根据环境管理与保护法案 第一条第五点…
as empowered under the EMPA, Article 1, Section 5...
快点
C'mon.
－我也可以直接开枪打死你 －对 但然后你要怎么办
Or I could just shoot you.
Yeah, but then what would you do?
你还少五张
You're short five.
NO ENTRY
－奥施康定  －氢可酮
- Oxy? - Hydro.
－多久以前的  －三个月
- How old? - Three months.
－亚特兰大来的  －我不知道他从哪弄来的
- From Atlanta? - I don't know where he gets 'em from.
－我只知道是真的 －如果是真的 就来自亚特兰大
I just know they're real. If it's real, it's from Atlanta.
联邦灾害对策局 在那里的隔离区有间工厂
FEDRA's got a factory down there in the QZ.
据说只生产两种东西
Supposedly only makes two things.
药丸和子弹 子弹和药丸
Pills and bullets, bullets and pills.
我猜你越常对人开枪就越难入睡
Well, the more you shoot people, the harder it is to sleep, I guess.
“你猜”
You guess?
你到底要不要
You want 'em or not?
袋子要还给我
I need the bag back.
－车子怎么样了  －都准备好了
- How we doin' with the vehicle? - All set.
只差仓库最后一个人需要买通
Just had to get one last guy in the depot to buy in.
好 要多少
Okay, how much?
那一班有四个人 加上我 总共六百
Four of them on that shift plus me... six hundred total.
听着 那些卡车会被报废是有原因的
Look, those trucks are shitheaped for a reason.
它们没有电池 我知道
And they don't have any batteries. I know.
我可以给其他人两百 你单独两百
I can see about 200 for the other guys... two hundred for you.
成交
Deal.
对了 帮你自己一个忙
Hey, do yourself a favor,
接下来几晚别上街
stay off the streets for the next few nights.
该死的火萤整周都在到处乱炸
Fuckin' Fireflies been blowin' shit up all week.
早上我们有两个人中弹 老大要我们连值两班
Two of our guys got shot this morning. Boss has got us working doubles.
大家都又紧张又累
Guys are jumpy and tired.
在黑暗中很容易失手
It's easy to make a mistake in the dark.
注意安全
Stay safe.
你也是
Yeah, you too.
（当你迷失在黑暗中时 就寻找光明）
WHEN YOU'RE LOST IN THE DARKNESS LOOK FOR THE LIGHT
你要我说什么 泰丝
What do you want me to say, Tess?
我没有要你说什么
I'm not askin' you to say anything.
最好是
Sure.
我又不是故意…
It's not
要骗你的
like I planned on rippin' you off.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
好
Well,
不如我们放下这件事吧
how about we just let it go?
不然你要怎样
What else are you gonna do?
你要把我关在这里吗 杀了我
Ya gonna keep me here? - Kill me?
－泰丝 拜托 －那罗伯特 你想怎样
- Tess, c'mon. Then, Robert, what do ya want?
－我要你忘记这件事 －没问题
I want you to forget this ever happened. Done.
－你少来 －怎么了 不过是卡车电池罢了
- Don't do that. - What? It's just a truck battery.
我付钱跟你买 你卖给别人 还花掉我的钱
I paid you for it, you sold it to someone else, and you spent my money.
你以为我没干过这种鸟事吗
I mean, you think I've never done shit like that?
－我的人把你揍惨了 －对 那就管管他们
- My guys fucked you up. - Yeah, so discipline them.
切掉一根手指或随便你想怎样
You cut off a finger or whatever the fuck you want.
我不在乎 他们是你的人
I don't care. They're your fuckin' guys.
那你的人呢
What about your guy?
等他看到你这副样子 你站在我的立场想想
'Cause when he sees you, - I mean, put yourself in my shoes.
听着 他对我唯命是从
- Look, he answers to me.
所以我向你保证 他不会伤害你
So, I give you my word that he won't hurt you.
我会跟他说我被几个家伙打了
I'll tell him that I got jumped by some guys,
然后你跟我就可以继续过日子了
and then you and I can just move the fuck on.
你干的好事已经毁了我这一周
Now your shit has pretty much ruined my week,
我只想回家喝酒 喝到脸不痛为止
and I'd like to go home and drink 'til my face stops hurting.
我们没事了吧
So, are we good?
对
Yeah.
所有市民必须立即撤离周遭区域
All citizens must clear the surrounding area immediately.
在联邦灾害对策局许可前不得返回
Do not return until FEDRA authorities permit.
所有市民必须立即撤离周遭区域
All citizens must clear the surrounding area immediately.
在联邦灾害对策局许可前不得返回
Do not return until FEDRA authorities permit.
所有市民必须立即撤离周遭区域
All citizens must clear the surrounding area immediately.
在联邦灾害对策局许可前不得返回
Do not return until FEDRA authorities permit.
所有市民必须立即撤离周遭区域
All citizens must clear the surrounding area immediately.
在联邦灾害对策局许可前不得返回
Do not return until FEDRA authorities permit.
所有市民必须立即撤离周遭区域
All citizens must clear the surrounding area immediately.
在联邦灾害对策局许可前不得返回
Do not return until FEDRA authorities permit.
该死
Oh shit.
火萤来了
Firefly, up top!
现在就解放波士顿 混蛋
Free Boston now, motherfuckers!
快开枪
前进…
－他们在开枪 他们在对我们开枪 －跪下…
- They're shooting. They're shooting at us. - On your knees. - On your knees!
不 我不是…
- No, no! I'm not a F--
我不是…我不是火萤的人
I'm not a Firefly!
－慢慢清楚地从一数到十 －一 二 三 四…
Count slowly and clearly from one to 10. - One, two, three, four--
慢慢数 数清楚
- Slowly, and clearly.
一
One.
二
Two.
三
Three.
四
Four.
五
Five.
六
Six.
七
Seven.
八
Eight.
去你的
Fuck... you.
现在伸出你的…
And hold out your--
－慢慢说出你的名字 －薇若妮卡
- State your name, slowly and clearly. - Veronica.
跟昨天一样 还有前天
Same as yesterday, and the day before,
还有大前天 还有…
and the day before, and the--
会有人来找我的 对策局的人 听到了吗
Hey, people are gonna come looking for me. People from FEDRA. You hear me?
放我出去 不然你们会付出代价 混蛋
Let me out or you're gonna pay, motherfuckers!
我不该在这里的
I'm not supposed to be here!
（当你迷失在黑暗中时）
WHEN YOU'RE LOST IN THE DARKNESS
听着 要排队
Hey, there's a line!
“告诉爸是个女孩”
"Tell Dad it's a girl.
“这是好事 对吧 ”
"That would be good, right?
“你想要孙女 爱你的贝卡”
"He wanted a granddaughter. Love, Becca."
留言结束 念出来
End message. Read back.
正确 ７３Ｋ奥兰多通话完毕
Correct, 73-K Orlando. Out.
没消息
Nothin'?
有没有可能是晚上传来的  你睡着所以漏掉了
Is there any chance it's comin' in at night? You're sleepin', you miss it?
我睡觉时 会由盖比瑞拉或我儿子负责监听
When I'm sleeping, Gabriela listens, or my son.
聪明的那个 不是另一个 上帝保佑他
The smart one, not the other one, God bless him.
如果汤米有回应 我们会知道的
If Tommy responded, we'd know.
你有跟塔台联络
- And you're talkin' to the tower?
每天都有 他们把你的留言转给他后 就再也没有他的消息了
- Every day. They gave him your message, they haven't seen or heard from him since,
就这样
and that's it.
－其实也不算很久 －已经三周了
- It hasn't been that long. - It's been three weeks.
他从来不会超过一天才回覆
It's never taken him more than a day to respond.
我相信他没事的
I'm sure he's okay.
告诉我塔台在哪里
Show me where the tower is.
你不是认真的吧
You can't be serious.
乔尔 那在怀俄明州
Joel, it's in Wyoming.
你得要长途跋涉
All this open country?
你是很厉害 但外面有比感染更糟糕的事
I mean, you're a capable guy, but there are worse things than Infected out there.
我全都听到了 有盗匪 有奴隶贩子
I hear everything on this. There are raiders, there are slavers--
但你确定汤米没事
But you're "sure" Tommy's okay?
是科迪塔 Ｑ４
It's the Cody tower...
但我不知道确切位置…
Q-Bar 4, but I don't know exactly wh--
下一位
Next!
你知道吗 乔尔
You know what, Joel...
乔尔
Joel!
我被几个家伙打了
I got jumped by a couple guys.
－什么人  －只是几个青少年
- What guys? - Just a couple teenagers.
说了一些不该说的话
Said some shit, probably shouldn't've.
拜托 你知道这些人 是在疫情爆发后出生的
Come on. You know these guys were born after the outbreak.
从没学过怎么吵架 只会直接动手
Never learned how to argue. They just start swingin'.
该死的１９岁小屁孩
Fuckin' 19-year-old pieces of shit.
你还活着真是奇蹟
It's a miracle you're alive.
我们所有人还能活着都是奇蹟
It's a miracle any of us are alive.
这不是新的伤口
These aren't new.
对
No.
我在对策局的监狱关了一整天
I was in FEDRA lockup all day.
总之这不重要
Anyway, it doesn't matter.
－我要你深呼吸 －什么事
- I need you to take a breath. - What?
－乔尔 －什么事
- Joel-- - What?
打我的人跟罗伯特是一伙的
The guys who jumped me were with Robert.
他把我们的电池卖给别人了
He sold our battery to someone else.
没有损失 这种鸟事难免会发生
Nothing's lost. Shit like this is gonna happen.
现在我们得振作起来
Now we just shake it off,
把配给卡或电池拿回来
and we go get our cards back, or the battery.
我需要电池 泰丝 没有电池 卡车就没用
I need the battery, Tess. Truck's no good without one,
如果我不快点找到汤米 他会死在外面
and if I don't get to Tommy soon, he's gonna die out there.
好吧 管他的 我们拿回我们的钱和电池
Okay, fuck it. We get our money back and the battery.
但乔尔 听着 罗伯特很怕你
But, Joel, listen, Robert is terrified of you.
要是你像克林伊斯威特一样冲出去 他会听到风声然后落跑
So, you march outta here all Clint Eastwood, he's gonna get wind of it and skip.
我要你先冷静下来
I need you to take a breath.
－他卖给谁了  －不知道
- Who'd he sell it to? - Don't know.
－他在哪里  －不知道
- Well, where is he? - Don't know.
还不知道
Yet.
但我们要悄悄查出来
But we're gonna find out, quietly.
明白吗
Understand?
我向罗伯特保证过你不会伤害他
Now I promised Robert that you wouldn't hurt him.
但我非常希望你狠狠教训他一顿
But I would very much like for you to hurt him.
所以我们去追杀那个混蛋
So let's go hunt that motherfucker down,
拿回我们的电池和卡车
and get our battery and our truck,
然后我们去找汤米 好吗
and then we'll go find Tommy. All right?
好
All right.
看看哪个比较合理
东南区的小队就位了吗
The team in place at Southeast 3?
我要他们暂停行动
I held them back.
我有几个问题
I have some questions.
好
Okay.
我们过去两周一直在漫无目的地 炸毁隔离区各地的对策局目标
We've been blowing up meaningless FEDRA targets spread out all over the QZ, for two weeks.
我们已经失去了四个人 我们…
We've already lost four people, and we're--
这有什么意义
What's the point of this?
这就是你的问题吗
Is that your question?
那是其中之一
That's one of them.
我的答案是你服从命令就好
My answer is to follow fuckin' orders.
你为什么把一个陌生女孩关在房里
And why do you have some random girl locked in a room?
你派去看守她的人什么都不告诉我
And the guys you have guarding her won't tell me shit?
我们的人在问怎么回事 我不知道该怎么回答
Our people are asking what's going on, and I don't know what to tell them.
叫他们服从命令
Tell them to follow fuckin' orders.
你们两个去东南三 立刻去
You two, go to Southeast 3. Now.
－琴 －玛琳
- Kim. - Marlene.
我们在对抗一个军事独裁政权
We are in a war against a military dictatorship
致力于恢复民主和自由 对吗
to restore democracy and freedom. Does that sound about right?
－对 －我们赢了吗 有打败对策局吗
- Yes? - Are we winning? Are we beating FEDRA here?
－火萤有在哪里打败对策局吗  －反抗需要时间
Are the Fireflies beating FEDRA anywhere? - Rebellion takes time.
如果你奋斗了２０年却一无所获 你就不能算是反抗军
- You fight for 20 years and you get nowhere, you're not a rebellion.
只不过是在到处涂鸦而已
Just spray paint.
我们不是在隔离区内 漫无目的地攻击对策局
We're not hitting FEDRA "all over" the QZ.
我们攻击这里…
We hit 'em here, here, here, here, here.
我们现在在哪里
Where are we right now?
我故意要对策局的人散布各处 除了这里以外
I want FEDRA everywhere but here.
我要他们尽可能分心
I want them as distracted as possible because tonight,
因为今晚 波士顿所有火萤成员 都会聚集在这栋大楼
every Firefly in Boston is gonna gather in this building,
我们要永远离开隔离区
and we are gonna leave the QZ. Permanently.
我们要放弃
- We're quitting?
不 我们要带那个 被关在房里的陌生女孩去西部
- No. We're taking that random girl locked in that room west.
这是我们在塞冷无线电塔的人传来的
From our guy in the radio tower in Salem.
这是真的吗
Is this real?
我相信是的
I believe it is.
别声张
Keep it quiet.
你需要什么都行 不惜一切代价
Whatever you need. Whatever it takes.
我们会送她去该去的地方
We'll get her where she needs to go.
朋友
Hey, friend.
别担心 我什么都不要
Don't worry. I don't want anything.
但如果你感到迷失…
But if you're feelin' lost--
叫我寻找光明 我就打断你的下巴
You tell me to "look for the light" and I'll break your jaw.
虽然花了我们几张配给卡 但我们逮到他了
Well, it cost us a couple of cards, but we got him.
据说他要把电池 送到一栋有红色记号的大楼
He's supposedly takin' the battery to a red-tagged building.
但大楼位于 史提尔曼街和克罗斯街的转角
But get this, corner of Stillman and Cross.
米盖尔以前用的那栋
The one Miguel used to use.
对 应该是
Yeah, I'm thinkin' so.
我们可以走干草市场下面的地铁隧道
We can take the subway tunnel under Haymarket,
从下面进入大楼 突袭罗伯特
get into the building from below, and take Robert by surprise.
我们狠狠还击
Pay this fucker back.
拜托
Oh, my God.
可恶
Agh! You fucker!
一 二 三 四
One, two, three, four--
你不怕吗
You're not scared.
那就把我解开
Then unlock me.
不如先说声谢谢吧
How about we start with "thank you"?
谢什么
For what?
救你一命
For saving your life?
如果你还记得的话 是我要他们别对你开枪的
I am the one who told 'em not to shoot you, if you recall.
是喔
- Yeah.
你为什么要阻止他们
Why did you stop them?
这个待会再说
We'll get to that.
那么 薇若妮卡
So, Veronica,
你感觉如何
how ya feelin'?
老样子
The same.
我会发病吗
Is it gonna happen?
不会
No.
那我可以走了吗
So, can I go?
不行
No.
我不会把这里的事告诉任何人 我发誓
I won't tell anyone about any of this. I swear.
你要去哪 回对策局军校
Where you gonna go? Back to FEDRA military school?
你那么想当军人吗
- You that anxious to be a soldier?
你以为我乐意去那里吗
- You think I chose that place?
我还是婴儿的时候 他们就把我送去那里了
They put me there when I was a baby.
那是收容孤儿的地方
It's for orphans.
不是他们把你送去那里的
"They" didn't put you there.
是我
I did.
艾莉
Ellie.
你该不会是我妈吧
You my fucking mom or something?
我看起来像你妈吗
Do I look like your mom?
不像
Nooo, you do not.
我叫玛琳
My name is Marlene.
我是波士顿隔离区的火萤首领
I'm the leader of the Fireflies in the Boston QZ.
为什么恐怖分子 会把我丢给对策局
Why would a terrorist dump me with FEDRA?
因为那是你最安全的地方
Because it's where you'd be safest, and you were safe there
你本来确实很安全 直到你决定偷溜出去
until you decided to sneak out.
恐怖分子
And "terrorist"?
莱莉是恐怖分子吗
Was Riley a terrorist?
你为什么不让我回家
Why won't you let me go home?
因为你有更远大的目标 远超过任何人的想像
Because you have a greater purpose than any of us could've ever imagined.
所以我们今晚就要离开 而且我们要带你一起走
So we're leaving tonight, and we're taking you with us.
－他来了 －给我五分钟
- He's here. - Five minutes.
我接下来要告诉你的事情 不能告诉任何人
What I'm about to tell you cannot be repeated to anyone.
因为如果你说了
Because if you do,
我向你保证…
I assure you
你会死
you will die.
好
Okay.
－准备好了吗  －好了
Ready? Yeah.
就是这个
That's the one.
可恶
Oh fuck.
该死
Oh shit.
这已经死了
This one's done.
对 我知道
Yeah. I know.
我只是一时被吓到
I just-- I wasn't expecting it.
我猜上次他不在这里
Take it he wasn't down here last time?
不在
No.
你觉得他是被感染后下来的吗
You think he came down after he was infected?
或者他就是在这里被感染的
Well, maybe down here is where he was infected.
我们继续走吧
Let's keep movin'.
看来他们把整栋建筑的构架都改了
It's like they reframed the whole structure.
可能是在１９８０年代做的
Probably in the '80s.
大家都缩减公寓大小 以便卖出更多单位
Everyone was cutting down on apartment sizes to sell more condos.
欢迎收看“乔尔米勒的工地现场”
"This has been 'Construction Corner' with Joel Miller."
我们要爬多高
How far up we goin'?
这么高
This far.
这里通往走廊
So, this opens into the hallway.
搞什么 有人把钢琴放在这前面吗
What the fuck? Someone put a piano in front of this?
你有闻到吗
You smell that?
有 火药味
Yeah, gunpowder.
泰丝
Tess.
电池不能用了
Well, the battery's no good.
他还是想卖掉
And he still tried to sell it.
还卖两次
Twice.
你这个贪心的混蛋
You greedy fuck.
不
该死
帮我一下 好了
Shit.
天啊 就…
Oh God.
好了
该死 加把劲
Shit, come on.
天啊
该死
Fuck.
乔尔
Joel?
玛琳
Marlene?
－你没事吧  －没事
- You okay? - Yeah.
艾莉…
Ellie. Ellie!
－该死 －不 没关系 我会没事的
- Oh shit! - No, it's okay. I'll be all right.
你不能干这种蠢事
And you can't be stupid like this.
罗伯特就是为了你摆我们一道
So this is who Robert screwed us over with?
波士顿的革命英雄
The Che Guevara of Boston?
战况一定很不顺利 你才会跟他这种人渣买货
War must be goin' pretty shitty for you to be buying from scumbags like him.
算是吧
Yeah, it kinda has been.
货很烂 但他显然不接受“滚蛋”这个答案
The merch was bad, and he obviously didn't take "fuck off" for an answer.
－把刀子还给我 －你要汽车电池做什么
- Gimme my knife. - What do you need a car battery for?
－不行 －不要指着她
- Don't. - Not at her.
指着我
Point it at me.
至于你问题的答案 我需要它有比你更好的理由
And to answer your question, I need it for a better reason than you do.
无意冒犯 但汤米只是一个人
No offense, but Tommy's just one man.
－掌握情报是我们的职责 －掌握情报
- It's our business to know things. -"To know things."
你就是罪魁祸首 是你让我弟弟跟我翻脸
You're the cause of it. You turned my own brother against me.
－好 乔尔 －枪声很响亮
- Okay, Joel. - That was a lot of gunfire.
－对策局肯定在路上了 －我知道
- FEDRA's gonna be on the way. - I know.
我们今晚本来要把艾莉带出隔离区
We were gonna move Ellie outta the zone tonight.
但这样我们哪也去不了 暂时还不行
But we won't make it anywhere like this. Not for a while anyway.
所以我在想…
So now I'm thinkin',
－你们带她走 －我们才不要
you're gonna do it. - The hell we are.
－我不要跟他们走 －让我带她走
- I'm not goin' with them! - Let me take her.
－泰丝 我们没时间扯这些 －是吗
- Tess, we don't have time for this. You don't have time?
－她是谁  －对你们来说 她是货物
- Who is she? - To you? She's cargo.
我们不走私人
We don't smuggle people.
－抱歉 －我可以的
Sorry. - I can do it.
琴 你是没长耳朵吗 给我闭嘴
- Kim, you don't have a fuckin' ear on your fuckin' head. Could you please?
有一群火萤的人在旧议会大厦等她
There's a team of Fireflies waiting for her at the old State House.
我知道外面有什么
I know what's out there.
所以我们派了一个小队过去
We were going with an entire squadron for that very reason.
但现在我没有卡车 没有小队
But now I don't have a truck, I don't have a squadron,
对策局再五分钟就到了 我只有你们
FEDRA's five minutes away. What I do have is you.
我很清楚你们两个的能耐
And I know what you're both capable of.
无论好坏
For better or worse.
他们有什么能耐
What are they capable of?
把她平安送到那里 他们会满足你们的需求
You get her there safely, and they'll give you what you need.
不只是电池 而是所有东西
Not just a battery. The whole thing.
加满油的卡车 枪 物资 通通都有 我发誓
Fueled-up truck, guns, supplies, all of it. I swear.
我发誓
I swear.
混蛋
Asshole!
你相信她吗
You trust her?
我也不信 但她好像很急
No, me neither, but she seems desperate.
火萤的车通常是用对策局的车改装的
Firefly vehicle usually means repurposed FEDRA stuff.
所以有很大的机会能开到汤米那里
So better-than-decent chance makin' it to Tommy in one of those.
我们把那小鬼交出去就走
The second we hand that kid over--
你们好好谈谈 但请记住 我血流不止
Y'all talk it through, but please remember that I'm bleeding out.
好 这样吧
Okay. Here's the deal.
我们会把她交给你们在议会大厦的人
We'll get her to your crew at the State House.
但在我们交出她之前 他们必须给我们想要的一切
But before we hand her over, they give us everything that we want.
－否则我们就当场杀了她 －成交
If not, we kill her, there and then. - Deal.
真的吗 想都不想
- Really? That fast?
你才是最重要的 我的团队不会危及这一点
You are all that matters. My team will not jeopardize that.
记住我跟你说的话 去拿你的背包
Remember what I told you? Now go get your backpack.
现在就去 艾莉
Now, Ellie.
我们走
Let's go.
乔尔
Joel,
别搞砸
don't fuck this up.
拜托
Please.
所有安全人员请至西区
给我们一分钟 好吗
Give us a minute, all right?
搞什么
What the fuck?!
计划是什么
So, what's the plan?
选择不多
There's not a lot of options.
不是走捷径就是绕远路
There's the short way or the long way.
走捷径会是一场恶梦
The short way is pretty much...
我们绕远路吧
That leaves the long way.
我们只要安全抵达就好
Things look bad, we'll come up with something.
交货之后去比尔和法兰克家
We'll have to drop, head to Bill and Frank's.
囤积一切我们可能需要的东西
Stock up on anything we may need.
（告示牌排行榜冠军单曲全集）
THE BILLBOARD BOOK OF NUMBER 1 HITS
我们天黑后出发 你跟那小鬼一起待在这
We leave after dark. Stay with the kid.
等等 为什么是我
Wait. Why do I have to-- Tess.
泰丝…
B/F
（６０ 没有）
60 - NOTHING IN
（７０ 新货 ８０ Ｘ）
70 - NEW STOCK 80 - X
比尔和法兰克是谁
So, who's Bill and Frank?
收音机播的歌是走私暗号 对吧
The radio's a smuggling code, right?
１９６０年代的歌代表他们没有新货
'60s song, they don't have anything new,
１９７０年代的歌就代表他们有新货
'70s, they got new stuff.
那１９８０年代呢
What's '80s?
－你在做什么  －打发时间
What are you doing? - Killin' time.
－那我要做什么  －我相信你可以自己想到
- Well, what am I supposed to do? I'm sure you'll figure that out.
你的手表坏了
Your watch is broken.
你睡觉时会说梦话
You mumble in your sleep.
我从没去过围墙的另一边
I've never been on the other side of the Wall.
你看那里有多黑
Look how dark it is.
你们常去外面吗
You guys go out there a lot?
－大概吧 －上次是什么时候
- I guess. - When was the last time?
－大概一年前 有差吗  －但你们知道该怎么走
Maybe a year. What's it matter? But you know where to go.
所以我们会没事的
So we're gonna be okay.
对
Yeah.
所以你到底是怎么回事  某个大人物的女儿吗
So what's the deal with you anyway? You some kinda bigwig's daughter or somethin'?
差不多吧
Something like that.
你睡着时收音机响了
The radio came on when you were sleeping.
什么 是什么歌
What? What was the song?
歌词一直重复“走之前叫醒我”
He kept sayin', like, "Wake me up before you go-go"?
该死
Shit.
骗到你了
Gotcha.
１９８０年代的歌代表有麻烦
'80s means trouble.
破解了
Code broken.
听着…
Listen--
兰开斯特街底下看起来不错
The spot under Lancaster looks good.
－你背包里有外套吗  －有
- You got a jacket in your pack? - Yeah.
好 去拿 该走了
Okay, get it. It's time to go.
遵守强制宵禁 对抗感染与叛乱
...mandatory curfew to fight infection and insurrection.
Observe mandatory curfew to fight infection and insurrection.
天啊 我真的跑到外面来了
Holy shit. I'm actually outside.
－天啊 －该死
- Jesus Christ. - Shit.
好 我们靠左边走缓冲区
Okay, we're gonna take the left edge around the buffer zone.
你要跟紧 听我指挥
You stay close and you follow my lead.
好 当然
Yeah. Yeah, of course.
我们走
Let's go.
搞什么
What the hell?
－不准动 －该死
Hey, hey! Don't, don't, don't move.
不准动
Don't move!
你在开玩笑吧
You gotta be shittin' me.
好 我们商量一下
- Okay, let's talk this out. - Turn around.
－转过去 跪下 －等等
- Hold on-- - Get on your fuckin' knees.
－给我跪下 －等一下
Get on your fuckin' knees! - Now hold on--
我是怎么跟你说的 我叫你待在家里
- What did I fuckin' tell you, man? I said stay the fuck home.
跪下
Get on your knees!
跪下就是了 跪下
Just get on your knees, just get on your knees.
听着 你让我们干这一票 我们就跟你平分配给卡
Listen, you let us do this run, we'll split the cards with you.
－是吗  －对
- Will you? - Yeah.
那我还真是太幸运了 手放在头上 眼睛看前面
I'm so blessed. Hands on your head. Eyes forward.
手放在头上
Hands on your head!
－真的吗 老兄  －对 我们得照规矩来
- Really, man? - Yep. We're doin' this by the book.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
好吧 给你四分之三如何
All right. What about three-quarters?
未经授权离开 你们会被吊死的
Unauthorized exit. They'll hang you for that.
好吧 这一票全给你 所有的药都半价
Fine. Everythin' off of this run, and half off on all of the pills.
半价 全部免钱
Half off? All off.
拿我的工作冒险只换半价  你真是疯了
Risk my job for half off. Outta your fuckin' mind--
－艾莉…搞什么  －该死
Ellie, Ellie! - Ellie, what the--  - Fuckin'
臭小鬼 可恶
bitch! Fuck!
给我让开
Get out of the fuckin' way!
－我们可以解决的 －让开
We can fix this. Move.
让开
Move.
－不 我没病 －乔尔
No, no! No, I'm not sick!
－我没病 你看 －乔尔…
- Joel! Joel, Joel! - I am not sick! I'm not sick!
你看 这是三星期前的
Look! Look! This is three weeks old.
没有人能撑过一天
Nobody lasts more than a day!
这看起来像一天前的吗
Does this look a day old to you?
－你们会杀了我的 －我真该杀了你
- You would've killed me! - I should fucking kill you!
－什么时候的事  －这不重要 你们得相信我
- When did it happen? - It doesn't matter! You have to trust me!
我们再不跑的话 他们会抓到我们的
They're gonna catch us if we don't run!
乔尔 我们得走了…
Joel, we gotta move. We gotta move, Joel!
乔尔
Joel!
（联邦灾害对策局 警告 生物污染区）
WARNING: BIOLOGICAL CONTAMINATION AREA DO NOT PROCEED
（请勿进入）
待续
谢谢观赏